# ADENIRAN OPEYEMI ADEWALE

<u>adeniran.opeyemi.ao@qmail.com</u> | 08113852536 7 Olufemi Street, Off Nathan, Surulere, Lagos, Lagos, LA

https://horpey.github.io | https://dribbble.com/tha\_ui\_guy\_

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Self-motivated web developer with a high level of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in a role with a company that promotes best practices and offers a wealth of customer projects.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## Skillset

- Languages: JavaScript, Jquery, HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, Python
- Framework: Bootstrap,
   Foundation, Vuejs, Angular,
   Codelgniter, Ionic, Django
- Development Tools: VSCode, Sublime.
- Database Platform: Firebase, MySQL
- **OS**: Windows, Mac OS
- Design Pattern: MVC

## **Personal Sills**

- Self motivated
- Team management
- Excellent communication skills

### **OTHERS**

- Dashboard design
- Website navigation
- Experience design
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Illustration
- Web design
- Code debugging
- Brand development
- Software projects

# **DESIGN SKILLS**

## **Tools**

Sketch, Illustrator, Photoshop, After effects, XD, Figma, InVision, Principle, Framer, HTML/CSS.

#### Design

Interaction Design, Visual Design, Motion Design, Wireframing, Rapid prototyping, Design exploration, Digital Illustration.

#### Research

Storyboarding, Interviews and survey, personas, journey mapping, Usability Testing, Competitive analysis

# **WORK HISTORY**

UI/UX Designer, Frontend Developer | Alpha and Jam Nigeria - Lagos, 12/2018-Current

- Develop new user-facing features
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders.

# Web Designer | Exolve Technologies Limited - Lagos, 04/2017-11/2018

- Created wireframes, screen-flow diagrams and UI spec documentation.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Conducted usability testing and post-deployment evaluations to measure user experience success.
- Developed site navigation by categorizing content and funneling traffic through content.
- Mentored interns in UX/UI Design Internship program.
- Designed images, icons, banners and audio enhancements.
- Completely updated and redesigned user experience for company website.
- Converted mockups into HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON.

# Graphic Designer | Tosh Crea8ions - Lagos 05/2016 - 02/2017

- Employed design fundamentals when selecting typography, composition, layout and color in design work.
- Used CorelDraw to create images and layouts.
- Built corporate brands by designing cohesive looks between elements such as logos and letterheads.
- Developed print materials such as brochures, banners and signs.
- Designed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks.
- Mentored new members of design staff during onboarding.
- Altered patterns to fit client requirements.
- Generated detailed specs of final designs.

## **EDUCATION**

Yaba College Of Technology - Lagos, LA

National Diploma: Computer Science

Iponri Estate Senior High School - Lagos, LA

Senior Secondary School Certificate (WAEC)

# ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Tutor at Girlcode Academy
- Community Mentor at <u>Developer Student Club, Unilaq</u>
- Mobile Web Specialist Scholarship <u>Udacity</u>. 2018
- <u>Daystar</u> Growth Academy 2017
- President, Iponri Estate High School Jet club 2012-2015
- Social Prefect, Iponri Estate High School-- 2012-2015
- Promenade Youth Initiative Training, 2013
- <u>Daystar</u> Leadership Course 2012
- Goge Africa Foundation Participation, 2010